Jensen, thank you for doing this today.
>> I'm happy to do it. Nice to see you.
>> It's nice to see you, too. Thank you for
your time. My first question, we've
heard from some of the top CEOs, Dario
Amadeday, Sam Alman, Elon Musk saying
that we need to pace the development of
AI. You've got whistleblowers saying
that the end of humanity could be within
10 years. Do you agree with this?
Well, first of all,
[clears throat and cough]
uh AI technology is is uh uh incredibly
powerful. It could of course do
incredible good and it could be applied
to uh uh terrible applications as well.
And so so we we have to make sure that
when we're developing this technology,
we develop it safely. And the industry
is transitioning from uh developing an
AI technology that was that was that is
becoming capable meaning that uh this
this first part of this year we went
through a transition where AI became
useful and it became useful uh the
demand for it is incredible. Uh token
generation of these AI products are now
profitable and actually incredibly
profitable. So many companies are
adopting it. Uh, OpenAI's latest Astra
is incredible. We're using it all over
the place. We use cloud code. We use
cursor. Uh, SpaceX SpaceX AI's product.
Uh, we use um, uh, cognition. And so the
capability of the technology has now
reached extremely useful state. And so
these companies are transitioning from
being a lab trying to get the technology
to work to now a products company. And
so in fact you know even calling it a
lab kind of tells you something. They
were in research for the first 1015
years and now all of a sudden in the
last six months practically the industry
has shifted to high production ramp
mode. And so so I think that all of the
all of the um the reactions um that are
happening are part of that transition at
its core.
>> Are they correct assessments of what
could happen? Are we all going to be, in
the words of some, gone in a decade?
>> No, that's that's completely false. And
that's that kind of narrative um uh is
dramatic. It gets a lot of attention. Of
course, obviously, it's gotten the
attention of of the press. And um I I
think at its core, they care deeply that
the products are built safely.
>> They're transitioning from a lab to
engineering.
um they have to dedicate a lot more of
their research researchers, a lot more
of their compute to safety. That's
that's um in in the case of developing
products, there's the engine, there's
the design part of it, the capabilities
part of it, and there's the verification
part of it. In the beginning of any
industry, most of the engineering goes
towards making the product work. And
then as the product becomes mature and
it rolls out into society, most of the
engineering is actually dedicated to
verification, testing, evaluation,
verification, benchmarking,
um uh attesting to standards, uh making
sure that that the product that they
ship uh is reliable, um it's functioning
as expected, uh delivers on the promise
of the product. And so it's very
sensible that right now during this
transition they have to move a lot of
their capabilities to AI safety. I think
that that's really where the the crux of
it. Um
any anything all the messaging around
the drama of it is unnecessary.
It's is quite frankly um uh too much
drama irresponsible. It is now grounded
on facts. It's not grounded on science.
>> So it's wrong. Well, it's f it's wrong
because it's not grounded on science.
Their their concern is not wrong. I just
want to make sure that at the core of
it, the concern is not wrong. This is no
different than I just landed from a
plane. I'm really glad that the the the
the entire ecosystem and industry of air
travel takes safety seriously and all
the people who are working around the
clock, they're more people working on uh
airline safety and aircraft safety and
air travel safety than they are working
on making uh new types of aircrafts. And
so it makes sense and and we're we're
just going through the same thing.
>> You've said we don't need any new laws.
We don't need any new regulations.
But you just said here that you support
safeguards in major industries. Why not
support the equivalent of an FDA or of
FAA for AI?
>> Well, before we come up with new new
laws and new regulations, let's apply
the current laws and the current
regulations. There are all kinds of laws
and regulations. You you know we live in
you know the land of laws and is the
reason why we feel safe and secure and
governed and and we have all kinds of
laws and regulations applied to each and
every one of those applications whether
it's food or um air travel or any
>> specifically for AI.
>> Yeah. So what's what's the what's the
missing part? Tell me the missing part.
I'm curious to know your opinion why you
think there are no missing parts when
someone like a Dario Amade or a Sam
Alman is saying we'd like to see
regulation.
>> I think I think the what I was
responding to is in the case of both of
the labs um one lab had four incidents
cyber security incidents uh triggered by
them. Another one uh just had a couple
more. And so so uh before both in both
of those incidents has plenty of laws to
deal with. You have cyber security
unauthorized entry uh uh uh laws. You
have um you have damage uh damage
liabilities. You have you know all kinds
of liabilities associated with cyber
security. Uh you have all kinds of
liabilities associated with products.
And so if your product does harm, if
your product doesn't perform as as you
promised, and if you entered into
contracts with companies for service
level agreements, there are plenty of
laws associated with that. My point is
apply those first and don't let don't
let this this doomsday narrative cause
somebody to relieve them of the laws
that currently exist. Now, go and go and
read between the lines. There's a lot of
there's they're actually not asking for
more laws. They're asking to be relieved
of the laws we do have. And I I think
that that's a problem. We have plenty of
laws. So, let's apply those first.
>> So, do you think then is are these
companies asking to be regulated in a
sense because they don't want to have to
handle this themselves and take their
own responsibility for what they're
building. Well, they're moving from a
lab to a products company,
from a from a uh from a a non uh
customer revenue producing to a customer
revenue producing business. And and that
transition must be extraordinary because
they're doing it so fast. And these are
two of the most consequential technology
companies in history. Uh they're
incredible, incredibly talented
researchers there. They're doing
excellent work, but it doesn't change
the fact. The fact is they're
transitioning from a laboratory into a
product service company generating tens
of billions of dollars of revenues,
expecting it to be hundreds of billions
of dollars of revenues. both of them
increasing their compute capacity at at
a rate no companies have ever seen in
human history. And uh and and and
deservedly so because their products are
good and they're and they're useful and
people want more of it and they like to
generate more revenues and their
investors want to see their growth and
and all of that is good. But there are
laws. There are product liability laws
and those product liability laws ought
to be tested against the current
incidents and um and the company well
then we'll see what happens next. Then
we'll see.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Do the do the
obvious first. Do the practical first
and then we can talk about the
theoretical later. But don't talk about
the theoretical without doing the
practical.
>> In making the argument for no additional
government regulation. I'm curious to
know.
>> So I'm I'm arguing for exercising
>> the current. Right. So but you are
saying you're not you don't advocate at
this moment for additional government
regulation
>> to do what?
>> Right. So if that's the premise
>> until until we know what's missing.
Until we know what's missing, why add
more laws? So on that note,
>> curious, do you have more faith in the
four or five CEOs who control this
technology than in additional
regulation? Do you trust them to do the
right thing and to
allay some of the fears here?
>> They're surely uh capable of doing the
right things. what they're going what
they're transitioning from and to is an
understandable thing. First of all,
they're all young CEOs, first- time
CEOs. I've been doing this for 33 years,
and I get the benefit of, you know,
hindsight and and to to sit here in the
back seat and pontificate about about
their business. Um, but the fact of the
matter is they're going through this
transition. It's not easy building a
company, building organizations,
building products, building industries,
building a business, going public. All
of that is new and it's all happening at
the same time.
>> And so I'm empathetic to the enormous
the enormity of the challenges that
they're dealing with. And I'm also I
also have a lot of confidence in in um
uh the capabilities of the teams that
they have. These are extraordinary
people. So you trust you trust
>> uh I believe in them. I believe in the
people. I also am empathetic of the
circumstances.
I don't approve of uh deflections and
distractions about the end of the world.
Um and and I rather them focus on the
things that I know they're focused on.
Their engineers are absolutely uh uh
able to understand that that that the
incidents they had requires them to
create more secure sandboxes and
isolation and containment of their
experiments. Um I am certain that they
have learned that they need to monitor
much more closely all of their software
as it's operating during testing and
eval. I am certain that if they were uh
uh if their if their uh software were to
interact with external from their cloud
interact with external clouds uh and
other services that they should let
people know and if incidents were to
happen uh to make sure that they share
it publicly so that the whole industry
can learn from it and we can all improve
ourselves. This is how the cyber
security industry works. You know I just
so you know right now all over the world
there's cyber attacks right
>> and there's all over the world engineers
are working feverishly to patch their
software improve their software improve
vulnerability. These are incredibly
complex systems. The fact that we have
open software and we have uh open-source
software so that all the companies could
defend themselves and upgrade their
software is one of the reasons why the
industry works and it's working right
now as we speak and we watch each each
other's back. there are hundreds of
companies that work together as a
community and um and you know we have
the as asymmetric benefit of having a
lot of defenders against attackers and
and so there's there's a lot of stuff to
to uh to unpack about the incidents they
had but it doesn't change the fact that
they're currently doing they're back to
grounding themselves in engineering.
They're going to improve their
engineering. They're going to invest a
lot more in evaluations and benchmarking
and testing and that's just a good
transition for them.
>> I'm curious, you know, as Americans look
at you, you're the CEO and founder of
Nvidia, this incredibly the most
valuable company in the world. Why
should on this specific issue of safety,
>> why should Americans trust your
perspective when your company's success,
your net worth is directly tied to
selling chips?
>> Our company's success is directly
connected to the safe deployment of
products and services. If the computer
industry doesn't provide value to the to
the world safely and productively um
provide enormously positive impact as we
have so far if we don't continue to keep
do if we don't continue to do that our
value would would be diminished and so
it is in our very personal and
industrial benefit that this new class
of applications called AI is able to be
produced and deliver to to the world
safely. We have to do this, you know, we
have to we have to balance this
responsible optimism. The reason why we
do what we do for a living is because we
believe it's great for the world. We
believe that we want our children to be
part of it. My children are part of it.
Um we want all of our families to be
part of it. We want this future where we
have less human suffering, where
companies could be more productive,
where we could discover knowledge more
quickly. We want all of this in the
future. We We want to deal with aging
populations. We want to have sustainable
energy and use AI market forces to drive
the world into sustainable energy. We we
want all of these things, but we have to
do it responsibly and we have to do it
safely. And we have to do this all with
maturity so that we don't scare other
people out of scare scare people uh with
dramatic and historical um prediction of
the future. That is just not true.
>> The elephant in the room here is the
race with China. H
>> the argument has been we can't slow down
AI progress lest we lose to China.
>> Do you think that's a valid argument?
>> Um
as an advice to every single CEO in
every industry, every student, every
professor, every member of the American
society, we want America to be as
prosperous as we can.
The more prosperous we are, the richer
we are as an economy, the more we could
provide for social security, the more we
could provide for national military
security, the the better we could be a
citizen of the world and support other
people's challenges and trials and
tribulation and pain and suffering, um
the more philanthropic we can be as a
nation. And so I would advise that every
single American citizen, everybody in
America pulls in the same direction as
hard as we can.
>> So should we slow down and would that
affect the race with China? The American
standing in
>> we should go as fast as we can
irrespective of anybody else. It's not
um if China were to discover a cure for
cancer, it's great for us. If China were
to uh invent a new technology for
sustainable energy, it's great for us.
If China were to uh uh lead in many
areas of science and math and we were
able to learn from them and benefit from
it, it's great for us. But listen, we're
packing heat as a nation. This is a
nation with extraordinary capability,
extraordinary innovators. I'm proud to
be part of the American technology
industry that I would consider
one of the three pillars of our national
treasures. Of course, our financial
system is one of them. Of course, our
military is one of them. You know, the
the the the industry that I serve, that
I'm part of, the technology industry is
absolutely one of our national
treasures. We are going to go as fast as
we can, but
>> how important is it? We're going to go
as fast as we can, but we would never
ever and never should
ship products before they're ready,
deliver products that are unsafe, and
nobody's expecting us to do that. But
everybody's expecting us to succeed and
help America be as prosperous as
possible. David Saxs told me earlier
this week that he believes that if we
slow down the rate of AI development,
then that could do huge damage to the
American economy, the American military
and put the United States at a
disadvantage. So I just want to clearly
understand like
do you think that
we should be pacing the development of
AI right now given where we are visav
China? First of all, David is incredibly
smart. Um,
this is thoughtful. He's deep. He's
pragmatic. Um, he is he is one of the
one of the great American patriots.
Um, it's been a privilege to to know him
and um I met him when he was an adviser
at the White House and um uh incredible
incredible human. Um, I'm not exactly
what what the context of what he said
was, uh, but I'm fairly certain he wants
America to go as fast as we can, but not
faster than we should. We should go as
fast as we can, but not faster than we
should. And if we're if we're
compromising safety, that can't happen.
Um, if you're compromising safety and
you deliver products that are unsafe,
that put people in harm's way, we have
laws of all kinds to come after you. And
so the companies that are developing
these technologies are perfectly
incentivized to do the right thing. And
I have every confidence. I have every
confidence because they're incentivized
to do so. They have the capability to do
so. that we will deliver, we will create
AI, advance AI in a way that's safe to
society.
>> Dario Amade says we should stop selling
chips to China. The quote is do not sell
powerful AI chips or semiconductor
manufacturing equipment to China. What's
your response to that?
>> Well, um we have to we have to make sure
that that uh technology that's created
by America advantage America first.
Every country would do that. Every
company does that. Every parent does
that. Every company does that. Every
industry does that. Every nation does
that. And in the case of in the case of
the American America has decided, the
United States has decided and and I'm
very supportive that we provide Nvidia's
best technology to American companies
first. And so we're in the generation of
what we call Vera Rubin. Vera Rubin is
shipping in volume production. Um we are
several years ahead of China with this
technology and um it's being made
available to uh to Dario and uh Sam and
you know the American labs and uh
American industries and that's exactly
what we're doing and we're we're
delighted to do that. Um on the other
hand remember that AI is a five layer
cake. It is not just that model. The AI
industry represent is represented by the
energy sector, the chips sector, the
model sector where where they are, the
model layer where they are. Um, you
could argue that there's six layers or
five, but above that is basically the
data and the application layer. And we
need every single one of these layers,
everybody in America to win. We want us
to win in the energy sector. We'd like
us to lead the world in the chip sector.
Uh, we like to make sure that every
single application company
I love the fact that FedEx is going to
be an AI company. I love the fact that
Walmart's going to be an AI company. We
need every single company in America to
be an AI company. Not just one company,
not just two companies. Remember, you
got to take a step back and remember
what what AI is. AI is intell digital
intelligence.
Why is it how is it possible that every
single company in America is not
supported and have capabilities of
digital intelligence? And so of course
every company is going to be a company
of the future with digital intelligence
or artificial intelligence as part of
the company. And so I want everybody to
win including the chips industry. And
so,
>> so you disagree with Daario's position
that we should not sell?
>> I completely disagree that uh we should
ban China of all American products.
The American company should have
advanced capabilities. But then after
that, every single layer of the American
AI tech stack, including the traditional
companies and the AI model companies of
every single field and every single chip
company should go and serve the world,
compete for the world. Serving the
world, having market have capturing
market share, capturing economic
prosperity, that's all about competing.
America is about competition and we
ought to go and compete and not seed
entire markets.
Our our market is not his to seed. Our
market is not his to seed. We ought to
go compete for the world's market.
>> I want to ask you about President Trump
and your relationship with him. Um
>> do you agree with President Trump?
You're one of his closest adviserss in
tech and AI.
>> He has a lot of adviserss. He has a lot
of advice [clears throat]
>> and he's he's an excellent listener.
>> Um he has a broad range of people he
talks to.
>> I'm curious
>> and I I that's that's one of the reasons
why he sees through these complicated
situations.
>> Well, speaking of that, yeah,
>> you know, he he said this week that he
believes that the concerns, the fears
about AI's dangers are a hoax. The
potential to destroy humanity with AI is
a hoax. Do you agree with President
Trump on this?
>> Oh, yeah. Now you and I started the
conversation just now with exactly this.
I completely disagree with that. I comp
I completely disagree that AI is going
to destroy is going to be the end of the
world um in 2030.
>> Do you agree? The president is calling
this fear a hoax. Do you agree with his
characterization of it?
>> Um
>> I just I was at the all-in summit
listening to you talk to him on the
phone.
>> Well, I don't want to speak for him. I
>> I'm asking you about you. I I believe I
believe the claims of the end of the
world um stirring fear across America
um
and doing it by the people who who are
doing it makes no sense to me. So they
must be doing it for ulterior reasons.
Um that's that's uh uh maybe it's
political, maybe it's otherwise, maybe
just attention grabbing, maybe so that
they could get a great interview with
you. Um I don't I don't know what is the
reason for it, but uh however it's
characterized, uh 2030 is not going to
be the end of the world. There is 0%
chance that's going to be the end of the
world. And so I I think that scaring
people is unnecessary.
it is irresponsible and I don't know
what their their motives are. Um,
however, uh, what he did say and some of
the other things. So, so that's one
thing that he said. The other thing that
he said was was that um, uh, we don't
need more regulations. Uh, we need to
apply the current regulations we have.
That's a very practical, very sensible
thing and and we just spoke about that
as well and I agree with that. He also
said something interesting um about his
ability to make sure that AI does not
have this impact on Americans. Uh do you
agree that President Trump has the
ability to fend off and prevent an AI
crisis while he's in office? You know
him, you talk to him. Does he have that
ability?
uh as the leader of of of uh of America
with all of the laws and regulations we
currently have um and recognizing the
incidents that we now have in front of
us uh I believe we have the necessary
laws and regulations to handle those
things and
>> so he can fend it off in your view
>> I yeah because America has our our
system already has a lot of laws and
regulations that applies to many
different sectors of products and
services and so so I think he's saying
practical things um and uh I and and
like like we've already spoken earlier I
I think we have lots of laws and
regulations and they should be applied.
>> I have two just quick questions for you
here. Um you will be attending the state
dinner with President Xiinping of China.
Is that correct? Next week.
>> Next week. Yes. if you get a chance to
speak to him about this situation that
we're in right now, the one that
Americans are so concerned about, what
will you say to the president of China?
>> Um, I would I would say that that um I'm
delighted to see uh AI's technology
transitioning from from laboratories to
now really useful capabilities and
products and services. And because it's
making that transition, it would be good
for um all countries that are developing
and advancing AI to do so in a way where
we share best practices. Um maybe maybe
set um uh global standards about uh
product expectations.
>> Work closer together.
>> Work Yeah, of course. Yeah, of course.
Work closer together. Um I if we want
look
they want China to be safe. They want
China to have the benefit of AI. They
want China to prosper just as we want
United States to prosper. I'm glad they
have ambitious
expectations and aspirations. I want I
wish every country Don't you wish every
country has aspirations and ambitions
for a better tomorrow? And I love that
about them. Um, as they advance the
technology, uh, we ought to make sure
that we work with each other as much as
we can, as much as we can. There are, of
course, areas where we we can't work
together for whatever reason. Um, maybe
it's militarily, well, it could be
military reasons. It could be um other
national security reasons that that that
um could arise. And uh, and those are
those are for for the governments to
sort out. Other than that, I think that
it would be great for us to work in
every possible way.
>> Um, can I ask you about something about
your your personal um, status here? I
mean, I I would be remiss to we all know
that Jensen Wong is the very successful
CEO of Nvidia. You are a billionaire.
You have said some of your fellow
billionaires here in California are
spending millions to fight Proposition
40, the billionaire tax as it were. You
have said that if California passes it,
you'd be perfectly fine paying it. Why
do you see it differently than so many
of your peers?
>> I don't mind paying taxes.
>> Why not?
>> Um, look, I don't like t I don't like
tax dollars wasted. Um, I like that our
country is efficient and runs
efficiently. U, but I also support uh
all that this country represents. Um, I
I support uh uh all of our government
officials um uh in their civil duties to
uh to make America great and and better.
Uh I love I love the infrastructure that
we've provided for all of our our
citizens. I love what it's created. Um
for me uh you know this is I am the
ultimate American dream and and um if
not for this country the education uh
the ability to create a new company
pursue your dreams uh and and let merits
be uh the reason why you succeed and
your your your endeavor your grit your
innovation let that be the reason why
you succeed. if not for, you know, why
I'm here. I I wouldn't have met all the
people that made Nvidia possible. I
wouldn't have met my wife in school. I
mean, there's the list goes on. I, you
know, I I love I love this country in
every possible way. And it's not
perfect, but it's incredible. And so I,
you know, I've had the benefit of
traveling around the world and I, you
know, sometimes looking back in on your
own country
>> and and um our all of our trials and
tribulations and discourse, you know,
the messiness of of our country in a lot
of ways, that's what makes it beautiful
and and it's what makes it work and and
um so I'm I'm delighted to to uh be part
of it.
>> Even if you might end up paying about
perhaps eight billion dollars over five
years still worth it?
>> Well, I think that that first of all,
I'm glad you said that. Um the fact that
I can afford to pay $8 billion in taxes
over five years is a privilege. It's not
that it it's not the $8 billion. It's
the fact that I can afford to pay$8
billion. And and so so um uh I'm not
afraid of paying taxes. I'm just afraid
of being poor and and [laughter]
I have no trouble contributing to
others. I love paying all I I'm famed
for for saying that I want to pay all of
our employees as much as I can and I do
instead of paying people as little as
possible to get their work. I try to pay
people as much as possible. That's a
that's a privilege of being successful.
and and um I that's you know frankly I'm
delighted to do it. Uh I I I feel it's a
privilege. It's a responsibility and um
nothing would give me more joy than to
pay be able to pay even more taxes.
>> Wait, are you asking to be paying more
in taxes?
>> No, the more you make, the more taxes
you pay. So I'm okay with that.
>> That's true. That's true.
>> I'm okay with that.
>> Well, Jensen, thank you. Um, do we have
time for a couple more questions or I
want to be respectful of your time.
>> I have all the time in the world.
>> Oh, you do?
>> It's my team.
>> Excellent. Well, I think I want to ask
you about something that's really
bothering a lot of Americans right now.
>> There's a lot of people who don't want
data centers.
>> Yeah.
>> In their backyards.
>> This is rare bipartisan
unity. The backlash is bipartisan.
NVIDIA powers a lot of data centers.
What do you say to the people out there
who are speaking out and saying we do
not want these in our neighborhoods?
>> Well, first of all, I would say um we're
sorry we didn't come talk to you sooner.
We should have come talk to them sooner.
um before before you even stand up a
giant data center in some community,
some rural rural area, some small town,
you know, I grew up I grew up in a town
uh of 600 people and I went to a school
with 300 kids and those 300 kids with
this that was Onita Onita in Kentucky,
that was it. And if you were uh if all
of out of nowhere a data center were to
crop up right next to the one grocery
store, um I think I I think I would be
alarmed. And and so I I think that that
first of all, we need to go engage the
communities long before we uh set up the
data centers. And I think uh all of my
colleagues uh recognize this today. You
know, it's just all of this happened so
quickly and it happened all over America
so quickly. uh uh sometimes we just we
just didn't have we we didn't realize um
and we didn't get a chance to be polite
to be to be a visitor in some some new
town. Um however I will also say uh um
the data centers are also improving
tremendously and tremendously quickly.
Uh the water the the the cooling system
is now is recirculating water. We use
hot water to cool the data centers and
so the amount of energy necessary the
amount of cooling necessary is
dramatically reduced. Uh the energy that
we we consume uh we should be providing
for the power generation plants. uh we
should contribute in fact even to the
local power grid enhancing it
reliability and one of the things that
United States uh is increasingly uh
understanding using the market dynamics
and the market forces of AI and just
this incredible investment phase the
first time in a 100 years we have an
opportunity to invest in all kinds of
sustainable energies where if if a
particular town would like solar if you
know if it like nuclear whether it's
fusion or fision
um hydro, every single form of power
generation is on the table today and
everybody is being invested in. And so
that's a fantastic moment. If we want a
sustainable future, the next five years
recognize no doubt we'll use much more
fossil fuel. But the the decades after
that, we're going to see all kinds of
applications of sustainable energy
because of artificial intelligence. And
so so I would say I would also say that
there are so many great stories of towns
that have been uh at the benefit of of
investments from the data center
builders. Uh you know their community
centers improved, new schools, uh new
baseball fields, new roads, uh uh lower
property taxes, all of that is on the
table. And so I think that that um uh
data center builders should go to go to
the communities, let them know that
they're considering building in the
community, let them know that the
conversation includes an opportunity to
upgrade their their town, uh lower their
taxes, lower their energy uh bill and um
uh and there should be some minimums.
There should be some expectation about
you know the the aesthetics of these
data centers. I think they ought to be
they ought to be designed better. They
could be designed better.
>> New a new approach to designing the data
center. Although the main concern really
is about
>> making making something beautiful is is
um just part of of uh the equation. I
think that today nobody considers the
aesthetics of a data center to be part
of its part of its functionality. Well,
people think a lot about the energy
bills and the the water and the
resources that go into it. That seems to
be the primary concern from people who
are protesting these data centers.
>> And so those things um
uh water consumption, that's a myth now.
Uh these data centers use less water
evaporative. They don't use evaporation
anymore. It uses less water than a
swimming swimming pool evaporating all
year long. And so so I think all of that
is kind of historic understandable but
it's a myth now. Uh energy energy bills
going up is actually the o the opposite.
Most of these data center all these data
centers uh should contribute to the grid
and and and um if they contribute when
they contribute to the grid it makes the
grid more resilient. They reduce the
power cost. Um,
>> it sounds like you're trying to say that
people should reconsider having these in
their neighborhood,
>> but that we should you should still do
it nicely. You should still make it more
aesthetic. The setback should be uh
further away from the towns. Uh because
you know the these data centers, there's
a lot of traffic in and out. There's
noise and so on so forth. And so you
just got to put it you have to be
sensible about these things. We have,
you know, we should we should have we
should have um uh very early on gone and
and had dialogue with the communities
before we showed up. It just happened so
quickly and so uh for that for that um
it's unfortunate. Uh but going forward
we can do a much better job.
>> You started this company you started
Nvidia as a gaming chip company. M
>> you were sitting in a Denny's
>> 30 years ago.
>> I was a dishwasher at the Denny's.
>> Yeah. That's where I I love Denny's. I
love Denny's. America's Diner. Who?
Yeah.
>> Did you ever think when you were a
dishwasher at Denny's that you would end
up on the front lines about a debate
regarding AI and the end of humanity?
>> Uh,
no. I was just really really uh focused
on doing doing dishes uh like no
dishwasher ever did dishes and um I was
the best bus boy of any bus boy that
ever bust tables. Um you know I I
brought enthusiasm to almost every job
that I had. It it didn't matter what it
was.
>> It seems like you're bringing that same
level of enthusiasm to your to your job
today.
>> This is consequential. This is
important. It's an important
conversation. I'm happy we're having it
and and um I want to make sure that that
the American public understands that
this industry will it is our
responsibility to build the technology
safely just as it is the drug industry
to build the drug safely the automotive
the car industry to build the cars
safely the plane industry to build the
plane safely this industry will build AI
safely we have to hold ourselves
accountable to that number one number
two uh don't let don't let the the myths
and the the ridiculous dramatic stories
uh cause us not to be optimistic about
this incredible capability. We do not
want to be the country that invented the
technologies of this industrial
revolution but have this country have
our country be left behind. Don't let
that happen. I don't want that happening
for my kids. I don't want happening for
your kids. Can you explain what data
centers actually do
>> and why
AGI
could be a good thing?
>> Okay. So, so really great question. Um,
first of all, so, so, um, uh, as you
know, several hundred years ago, about
350 years ago, uh, the modern industrial
revolution started. Electricity was
being manufactured. It was a mis it was
a magical thing a almost a mythical
thing where you could have uh water come
into this machinery and this invisible
technology comes out of it called
electricity and we can transport energy
all over the world replacing candles and
and uh and stoves and and wood burning
ovens and so on so forth, steam engines
and and so we we made it possible uh for
this new industry to happened and a
whole industry was built on top of it.
Then the second indust the next the last
industrial revolution uh was really
about the information age and we made it
possible by building these data centers
uh for the internet to be connected
together so that we can uh find anything
>> and so the fir the the previous
industrial order we could power
anything. Now we can find anything and
where we are today we created this
technology called artificial
intelligence where given information
given context it can reason about it can
reason about the information that you
gave it so that it can answer and do
anything. You can even use tools like
for example instead of you and I using a
web browser or you and I using uh
PowerPoint Excel or you know a 3D design
tool called you know AutoCAD or Blender
or something like that. This software
can reason about what you asked it to do
take the context the information that
you need it to do your intentions and it
does the work for you. And the latest
generation from OpenAI called Astra is
incredible. You just tell Astra, "Here's
a picture of my backyard. Um, here's
some other uh here's some examples that
I would like, maybe a pool or a garden I
like to place in it. I want you to now
turn it into a design file for my
gardeners and my carpenters so that they
could do that backyard for me or design
that house for me, um, build that house
for me." And so Astra uses all the
necessary tools and the images that you
gave it and it creates the CAD files for
the house or the kitchen or the
backyard. It's incredible. And so that's
what AGI does. Now what what is
necessary, however,
is we now need a new type of
infrastructure. Instead of a power
generator,
instead of a data center for the
internet, we now need a artificial
intelligence AI factory. It's an AI
factory. Energy comes into it, data
comes into it, and these numbers we call
tokens, but basically reformulated into
intelligence. I know that sounds
complicated, but basically
energy comes in, intelligence comes out
and it it basically is an AI factory.
>> Input output.
>> Input output. It's as simple as that.
And of course, these factories have a
lot of computers inside that Nvidia
makes. And and so now the question is um
uh how big would this industry be? Now
it turns out that just about every part
of the economy and every human uh we
like to know things. We're like we like
to do things. Maybe we like to, you
know, automate our shopping. Maybe we
want to u automate the planning of a of
a vacation or a trip and find us the
best fairs. Um uh so on so forth. I just
gave you the example of maybe we want to
improve our backyard or design a new
kitchen. And so every single industry
has information work to do and with the
world's industries call it a hundred
trillion dollars of economy and out of
that some 15 trillion dollars of it um
would benefit from more intelligence uh
than it currently has. And so these
factories is a layer that goes around
every single country. Every company will
use it. And um that's the reason why
there's so many of these data centers.
This is going to be a multi-t trillion
dollar industry. Now the question the
question then becomes how do we think
about these data centers from America's
perspective. And and so the thing to
realize is that this is the first time
in a 100 years well at least first time
in 50 years that we have an opportunity
to reindustrialize the United States
meaning bring manufacturing back to
United States. Now, of course, this is
manufacturing of something that's
invisible, just like power generation
was.
>> Not exactly your car manufacturing.
That's right. Tradition.
>> It's not manufacturing atoms. It's
manufacturing electrons. Okay. If you
will, it's invisible. And and um uh but
it's manufacturing nonetheless. And it's
creating all kinds of manufacturing jobs
across the United States as you know. uh
the the construction workers,
electricians, the the fitters, the the
designers, the the builders, everybody
is so incredibly busy because they're
building out the several trillion
dollars worth of AI factories across
America. And so this is the part that is
really exciting to me is that this is
the first time in several decades that
the the bluecollar workers, the the
builders, the crafts people are of our
country, this is their great
opportunity. and all of them are
enjoying such prosperity now. And I I
love seeing that we we have a real
shortage of electricians and and and
construction workers. But this is just a
wonderful opportunity for United States
to re-industrialize, be a manufacturing
country again, for us to um uh uh create
opportunities for the blue collar
workers and and all the builders of our
of our of our country and to bring back
building and manufacturing again. And so
I think it's incredible. So it's
creating all kinds of jobs.
>> A lot of people don't see data centers
as a manufacturing story. So I think
it's interesting.
>> That's right. Yeah. It's just a new
version of manufacturing just as I as I
said earlier. Um power generation is a
man it's industry. Power generation is
industrial and you have people in there
that's building these factories and and
uh it has to be built. It's built by
builders and data centers are just
manufacturing the new version. Um, and
this new version and of manufacturing
products is it's invisible. It's
numbers. I know it's it's weird to be
manufacturing numbers. Um, but that's
essentially what it is.